[Music]
[音乐]
thank you everybody thank you for
谢谢大家，谢谢
staying this late in the day I know
我知道要熬到这么晚
after this many sessions for this many
在这么多会议之后
hours it really really gets tough I'm
几个小时，我真的很难受
even flagging a bit at the end of today
甚至在今天结束时有些微不足道
so as we heard a little bit earlier my
所以就像我们早些时候听到的
name is Ben Hale I run both the r2d BC
我叫本·黑尔（Ben Hale）
project which we talked a little bit
我们谈了一点的项目
about this morning in the keynote but I
关于今天早上在主题演讲中，但我
also run Java on Cloud Foundry so the
也可以在Cloud Foundry上运行Java，因此
big open source pass project and I run a
一个大型的开放源代码传递项目，我运行了一个
lot of Java strategy for pivitol itself
Pivitol本身的许多Java策略
and so it's probably weird to hear me in
所以听到我的声音可能很奇怪
the keynote are talking now about
主题演讲现在正在谈论
reactive programming right like clearly
反应式编程就像清晰
I'm in charge of this cloud thing and I
我负责这件事，我
do a lot of strategy so what exactly you
做很多策略，那么你到底是什么
know it sort of brings me here why am I
知道这把我带到这里的原因
such a fan of reactive programming and
这样的反应式编程爱好者
the answer is in my position working
答案在我的职位上
with cloud foundry customers I see a lot
与云代工客户一起，我看到了很多
of people who have you know gone from
有您认识的人
this monolith inside their own data
他们自己的数据中的这个整体
center sort of a sunk cost kind of thing
中心沉没成本之类的东西
and they start taking a look at their
他们开始看看他们的
bills to Amazon or their bills to
账单到亚马逊或他们的账单到
pivitol as they start expanding and they
己糖醇，因为他们开始扩大，他们
start doing micro services and they
开始做微服务，他们
start seeing some of these problems that
开始看到其中一些问题
we described a little bit earlier and so
我们早一点描述了，所以
it became very clear to me that sort of
对我来说很清楚
efficiency is a really really key
效率是非常关键的
imperative for a lot of our customers
对我们许多客户而言势在必行
and so just to reiterate again what I
所以只想再次重申一下
said this morning reactive programming
说今天早上反应式编程
we you know sort of in the spring
我们知道 Spring
community and pivotal as well we
社区和关键的我们
definitely view reactive programming as
绝对将反应式编程视为
the next frontier in Java for
Java的下一个前沿
high-efficiency much more even than high
高效率甚至比高效率
performance efficiency in a way that we
表现效率
sort of forgot about it over the last
在过去忘记了它
two or three decades has now sort of
两三个十年现在有点
come back to the forefront your team
回到您的团队的最前沿
your tree Pizza team is likely
你的树比萨团队很可能
responsible for a very discrete bit of
负责非常离散的
your AWS bill so now all of a sudden you
您的AWS账单，所以突然之间您
start having to think about that a
开始不得不考虑一个
little more what we're talking about
多一点我们在说什么
reactive programming again you've all
再次进行反应式编程
seen a lot of this stuff but let me just
看到很多这样的东西，但让我
touch on it one last time reactive is
最后一次反应是
fundamentally non-blocking and it's
基本上是非阻塞的
often paired with asynchronous behave
通常与异步行为配对
but what's a big surprise to a lot of
但令很多人惊讶的是
people as asynchronous is not actually a
人们异步并不是一个
key part of being reactive reactive has
反应性的关键部分
no opinions on this in fact if you took
实际上，如果您采取了任何意见
a look at much of the reactive code that
看看很多反应式代码
you've seen on slides all day today the
您今天整天都在幻灯片上看到了
vast majority of the code that you're
您所使用的绝大多数代码
seeing there actually executes
看到那里实际执行
completely synchronously in fact
实际上完全同步
something like Project reactor has this
像Project Reactor这样的东西
thing internally that it's an
在内部，这是一个
optimization that allows it to take a
优化使其可以
look at a bunch of different operators
看一堆不同的运算符
which are you know sort of programmed in
你知道哪种编程吗
a way that it could go in a an
它可以在一个
asynchronous or in a multi-threaded way
异步或多线程
and it fuses them all together to
并将它们融合在一起
execute them in a single thread as
在一个线程中执行它们
quickly as it possibly can right so much
尽可能快地解决问题
of the reactive code you write actually
实际编写的反应式代码
is synchronous but where it can be
是同步的，但可以在哪里
asynchronous when you're going across
穿越时是异步的
the network when you're going to a
网络，当您要去
database something like that we end up
数据库这样的东西我们最终
with this you know really good match
有了这个，你知道真的很合适
between a reactive programming model and
在反应性编程模型和
an async programming model but that's
异步编程模型，但这是
not enough right like it's not enough to
不够，就像这样还不够
say that async is a thing or
说异步是一回事，或者
non-blocking is a thing we've had those
不阻塞是我们拥有的那些东西
kind of api's before we have Java and IO
Java和IO之前的一种api
and things like that when we talk about
当我们谈论这样的事情时
reactive in that reactive manifesto
反应性宣言中的反应性
talking about the reactive streams
谈论反应流
project one of the really key elements
项目真正关键的要素之一
the real game-changer for reactive over
真正的反应力改变者
just pure non blocking or acing is this
只是纯粹的非阻塞或刺激是这
idea of pull pushback pressure or
拉推压力的想法或
reactive back pressure there's this idea
反应背压有这个想法
that in many systems that need to be
在许多系统中需要
resilient we see the same problem
有弹性的我们看到同样的问题
pattern happening again and again we're
模式一次又一次地发生
a publisher someone who's allowed to
发行人被允许
send data to a subscriber a consumer of
向订阅者的用户发送数据
that data the publisher can overwhelm
发布者可以压倒的数据
that subscriber right it can overwhelm
那个订户对它会不知所措
that consumer in a way that means the
该消费者以某种方式
consumer blows up because it gets filled
消费者因为充满而炸毁
up its caches get filled up and too much
它的缓存被填满了，太多了
data is there or the publisher
有数据或发布者
potentially as its trying to jam as much
可能会尽可能地阻塞
data as it can down the pipe it might
数据，因为它可能会下降
blow up as well so reactive is all about
也会炸毁，所以反应就足够了
this idea of saying no you publisher
拒绝发行商的想法
aren't allowed to send to me until I
直到我被允许发送给我
tell you that I pull the next eight
告诉你我拉下八个
items in the next ten items what have
接下来的十个项目中有哪些
you from there and again so we start
你从那里一次又一次，所以我们开始
seeing this if you saw
看到这个，如果你看到了
juergen x' talk in the last section he
Juergen x'在最后一节中的讲话
talked about this quite a lot as well we
我们也谈到了很多
really like Webb flux right Webb flux
真的很像韦伯助焊剂对韦伯助焊剂
was really useful to us it has this
对我们真的很有用
thing called a web client this is very
所谓的网络客户端，这是非常
weird for me normally I do this in a
通常对我来说我很奇怪
much smaller room so I can walk over and
小得多的房间，所以我可以走过去
point it something on the screen I'm
将其指向屏幕上的某物
gonna just wave at that there a little
只会在那儿挥手
bit here we have this idea that there is
有点在这里，我们有一个想法
a web client that is fundamentally
根本上是一个Web客户端
reactive and it allows us to effectively
反应性的，它使我们能够有效地
define what needs to be sequential and
定义需要什么顺序
what can be parallel right so what this
可以并行的是什么呢
is saying here is I want to use the web
在说这里是我要使用网络
client to get two different service URLs
客户端以获取两个不同的服务URL
I can do them in parallel mono dot zip
我可以并行做单点拉链
there says these two things can happen
那里说这两件事可能发生
in parallel and as soon as both of them
并行并尽快
are complete I want you to coordinate
完成了，我要你协调
that and run the next thing sequentially
然后依次运行下一件事
this transformation this map to a
将此地图转换为
composite type so effectively what
复合类型这么有效
you're getting here is the ability to
你到这里是有能力
define sort of programmatically or
以编程方式定义排序或
declaratively what can happen in
声明性地会发生什么
parallel and then what has to happen
并行，然后发生什么
sequentially after that and depending on
之后，并取决于
your reactive framework reactor in this
您的反应式框架反应器在此
case project reactor to work out what
案例项目反应堆可以算出什么
can be thread sorry what can be done
可以线程抱歉，该怎么办
single threaded what can be done
单线程可以做什么
asynchronously what coordination needs
异步需要什么协调
to happen how to properly allocate
发生如何正确分配
efficiently all of the thread usage
高效地使用所有线程
that's around there and so this is
在那附近，所以这是
really lifting a burden there's nothing
真的减轻了负担
to stop you from doing these things
阻止你做这些事情
yourself you could use you know sort of
你自己，你可以用你知道的
fork/join pools you could use new thread
分叉/联接池，您可以使用新线程
and join on that but this frees you from
并加入其中，但这将您从中解放出来
that allows you to describe the
可以让您描述
structure of these requests the
这些请求的结构
structure of these behaviors separately
这些行为的结构分别
from the threading of them but there are
从他们的线程，但有
still some barriers to reusing reactive
重用反应性仍然存在一些障碍
everywhere I put a little ash track
我到处都放了些灰烬
there I find that as people use reactive
我发现随着人们使用反应性
programming a lot they eventually become
编程很多，他们最终成为
zealots about it and absolutely believe
狂热者对此深信不疑
that everything should be done
一切都应该做
reactively this is not the position of
反应地这不是
the spring team this is not the position
The Spring Team 这不是职位
of anybody at this conference reactives
这次会议上任何人的反应
great but there are places where it's
很棒，但是在某些地方
really really useful and places where it
真的非常有用，并且在哪里
might not be quite as useful so when we
可能没有那么有用，所以当我们
say using reactive everywhere maybe
说可能到处都使用反应式
let's say we're using reactive
假设我们正在使用反应式
everywhere it's appropriate as I
到处都适合我
mentioned earlier today cross process
今天早些时候提到的跨进程
back pressure is one of those barriers
背压是这些障碍之一
and so we work on the our socket project
所以我们在进行套接字项目
and I have a talk tomorrow afternoon on
明天下午我会谈
that but also in the data access realm
还要在数据访问领域
where we see some of the no sequel
我们看到了一些续集
databases that exist today have reactive
今天存在的数据库具有反应性
access or have asynchronous access it's
访问或具有异步访问权限
good enough for us to write reactive
足以让我们写反应式
drivers on top of but we don't have that
司机，但我们没有
relational database access until now one
关系数据库访问到现在为止
of my friends in the and the audience
和观众中我的朋友们
mentioned to me I missed the perfect
提到我，我错过了完美
opportunity this morning this is the
今天早上的机会是
Droid you're looking for in fact so are
您实际上正在寻找的Droid也是如此
two DBC is an API designed from the
两个DBC是从
ground up for reactive programming just
为反应式编程而准备
to reflect again on what those design
再次反思那些设计
principles were behind this particular
特定原理背后
project so the design principles are
项目，因此设计原则是
that we want to make sure we use
我们要确保我们使用
reactive streams types there's a bunch
反应流类型有很多
of different ways to write reactive
编写反应式的不同方法
programming certainly before the
当然在之前编程
reactive streams project came into
反应流项目进入
existence and standardized that there
存在并标准化那里
were a bunch of different projects that
有很多不同的项目
did different things but we want to say
做了不同的事情，但我们想说
that the community has chosen right the
社区选择了正确的
community has sort of voted with their
社区已经对他们的投票
feet voted with their their programming
脚投票赞成他们的节目
and has decided that reactive streams is
并决定反应性流是
the way we do high-efficiency
我们高效的方式
programming and jobs so we want to make
编程和工作，所以我们想做
sure that we're native there we don't
确保我们不是那里的本地人
want to be a layer below we don't want
想要成为我们不想要的一层
to be a layer above we want to be at
成为我们想要的一层
reactive streams we want to be
我们想要成为的反应性流
completely non blocking all the way to
完全不阻塞
the database including possibly because
数据库可能包括
not all databases allow this utilize
并非所有数据库都允许这种利用
wire protocol features to get this kind
有线协议功能来获得这种
of non-blocking behavior I think one of
我认为非阻塞行为之一
the key things that people we're going
我们要去的人的关键事情
to talk about this a little bit later in
稍后再谈论这个
the towards the end of this but one of
即将结束，但其中之一
the key things about our two DBC is that
关于我们两个DBC的关键是
it's a spec and we write implementations
这是一个规范，我们编写实现
for it and those implementations they
对于它和那些实现他们
don't build on top of anything that
不要建立在任何东西之上
exists today they don't build on top of
今天存在，他们不建立在
JDBC drivers that already exists because
已存在的JDBC驱动程序，因为
all of those things are blocking api's
所有这些东西都阻塞了api
what we actually have to do is re
我们实际上要做的是
implement from scratch but writing
从头开始实现，但写作
binary frames and Java code and
二进制框架和Java代码以及
implement the wire protocol for all of
为所有实施有线协议
these databases so this gives us an
这些数据库，所以这给了我们一个
opportunity to make use of features in
有机会利用功能
those wired protocols in those
在那些有线协议
networking protocols between clients and
客户端与
databases that give us really good
给我们非常好的数据库
non-blocking asynchronous behavior the
非阻塞异步行为
third principle is and this is really
第三个原则是，这确实是
really
真
counterintuitive to a lot of people we
对很多人而言，我们违反直觉
want to shrink the driver of the SPI to
想要将SPI的驱动器缩小到
the minimal set of operations that are
最小的一组操作
implementation specific even if that
即使具体实现
means that using our 2 DB C is really
意味着使用我们的2 DB C确实
difficult for end-users this seems
对于最终用户而言，这似乎很困难
totally counterintuitive don't I want
我完全不符合直觉
this to actually be usable for end users
实际上可供最终用户使用
but we view our 2 DB C as a
但是我们认为2 DB C是
specification that users will never see
用户永远不会看到的规范
what we want to do is build a really
我们要做的是建立一个真正的
nice even foundation so that clients can
好的基础，使客户可以
be built on top of it these humane api
在这些人性化的api之上构建
is in a way that r2 DB c itself isn't
r2 DB c本身不是
and the reason that is is because i
那是因为我
don't know what kind of client api you
不知道您使用哪种客户端API
actually want are you the kind of person
其实想要你是那种人
who really likes JPA with a full ORM on
谁真的很喜欢JPA并附有完整的ORM
top of it are you the kind of person who
最重要的是您这种人
likes spring data repositories where you
喜欢Spring 数据存储库
write an interface that automatically
编写一个自动
does some sort of mapping for you
为您做某种映射
are you more an i badass person or
你是我的坏蛋还是
somebody who likes a flew into API like
喜欢飞入API的人
JD bi I don't know and I don't think
JD bi我不知道，我不认为
that we should specify it as part of
我们应该将其指定为
this spec and that's that's driven by
这个规范，那是由
the idea that it turns out one of jdbc
原来是jdbc之一的想法
c's biggest failings whenever we talk to
每当我们交谈时，c的最大失败
any of the sort of client implementers
任何类型的客户实施者
that sit on top of it like hibernate or
坐在它上面的像冬眠或
something like that or even the database
这样的东西甚至数据库
vendor implementers of the drivers
驱动程序的供应商实施者
themselves people like the the Postgres
他们自己喜欢Postgres
or my sequel team is that JDBC was sort
还是我的续集小组认为JDBC是排序
of built 20 years ago sort of in a in a
建于20年前
world where everybody thought you just
每个人都以为你只是的世界
used JDBC driver which meant it had not
使用了JDBC驱动程序，这意味着它没有
only all the api's that were necessary
只有所有必要的api
excusing for programmatic access to
借口以编程方式访问
these databases to build these clients
这些数据库来建立这些客户端
on top of but it also had humane api's
最重要的是，但它也具有人性化的api
driven into it as well things like
以及诸如此类的东西
binding humane affordances like the
具有约束力的人道能力
question mark which then they chose one
问号，然后他们选择了一个
index instead of zero indexed unlike
索引而不是零索引不像
everything else in programming so what
编程中的其他所有内容
we ended up with was a an API that
我们最终得到的是一个API
nobody liked right users don't use it
没有人喜欢合适的用户不使用它
almost nobody in this room I'm pretty
这个房间里几乎没人
sure actually uses the JDBC API in fact
确保实际上实际上使用了JDBC API
I didn't ever use the JDBC API by the
我从来没有使用过JDBC API
time I started Jurgen and rod had
当我开始Jurgen和Rod的时候
already written the JDBC template inside
已经在里面写了JDBC模板
of spring so that's you know
Spring 的那就是你知道的
sort of 13 years ago 14 years ago and so
大约13年前14年前等等
I started immediately with that it was
我立即开始
so much better than trying to use the
比尝试使用
JDBC API but then at the same time
JDBC API，但同时
driver vendors hate it as well because
驱动程序供应商也讨厌它，因为
they end up repeating a lot of
他们最终重复了很多
functionality across all the different
跨所有功能
drivers Postgres team has to implement
驱动程序Postgres团队必须实施
question mark binding the my sequel team
问号约束我的续集团队
has to implement question mark binding
必须实现问号绑定
everybody's got to implement URL parsing
每个人都必须实现URL解析
and they've all done it differently
他们都做了不同的事情
right so there are big problems with how
对，所以在如何使用方面存在很大的问题
JDBC API was designed in the first place
JDBC API是最初设计的
so we have designed an API and this is
所以我们设计了一个API，这是
sort of very much still under
有点仍然在
development we're in early days of RTD
在RTD的早期发展
BC but what we've designed is an API
BC，但我们设计的是API
that tries to eliminate a lot of that so
试图消除很多这样的
what you're going to see here we're
您将在这里看到的内容
gonna go through a bit of the API and
将通过一些API和
we're going to sort of get a view of the
我们将有点了解
different pieces and how they interact
不同的部分以及它们如何相互作用
and what a programming model might look
以及编程模型的外观
like and you're gonna see a lot of
喜欢，你会看到很多
parallels between what you saw on JDBC
您在JDBC上看到的相似之处
but in a reactive way with some
但以某种反应的方式
improvements to it so the very first
对它的改进
thing in the driver SPI is this idea of
驱动程序SPI中的内容是
a connection factory a connection
连接工厂连接
factory allows you to create a
工厂允许您创建一个
connection get some metadata about this
连接获取有关此的一些元数据
connection but the very first thing
连接，但第一件事
you're going to see on this API
您将在此API上看到
literally the very first line is that
实际上，第一行是
when you call create you don't actually
当您调用创建时，您实际上并没有
get a connection you get a publisher
建立联系，获得发布者
which is a reactive streams type that
这是一种反应流类型
says at some point in the future after
说以后的某个时候
you subscribe to me I will give you a
你订阅我，我会给你一个
connection to do some sort of work with
连接以进行某种工作
write this sort of lazy binding message
编写这种惰性绑定消息
driven kind of behavior that you expect
期望的行为驱动
from reactive given that connection
从反应的给定连接
that's where some really interesting
那是一些非常有趣的地方
stuff gets to happen in this is where we
事情发生在这是我们
can do things like close the connection
可以做一些事情，例如关闭连接
pretty straightforward we can manage
我们可以管理的非常简单
transactions such as beginning them
诸如开始交易之类的交易
setting there's isolation level
设置隔离级别
committing and rolling them back right
提交并回滚正确
we see that you can manage save points
我们看到您可以管理保存点
whether creating them releasing rolling
是否创建它们释放滚动
back to them you can create batches you
回到他们，您可以创建批次
can create statements we're really going
可以创建我们真正要去的语句
to focus on the create statement coming
专注于create语句的来临
up but one of the things you're gonna
上升，但你要做的一件事
see is a lot of these actually have a
看到很多这些实际上有一个
very similar well at exactly similar
非常相似，非常相似
idiom they return publisher void so if
他们成语使发布者无效，所以如果
you think back to how exactly reactive
你回想起到底有多反应
programming works
编程作品
you're always saying something will
你总是在说些什么
happen in the future when you subscribe
当您订阅时发生
to me you can't actually ever return
对我来说你实际上永远不会回来
void right the concept is saying I'm
无效，这个概念是说我
gonna call a method and you'll return
要调用一个方法，你会返回
void to tell me when you're done because
告诉我你什么时候做完，因为
I don't know when void would actually be
我不知道什么时候虚无
returned I don't want to block waiting
返回我不想阻止等待
for it so in the reactive world this
为此，在被动世界中
idea of publisher void this thing that
发布者的想法使该东西无效
will signal completion but never
将表示完成，但永远不会
actually send any data is how we
实际发送任何数据是我们的方式
represent that so when you can't begin
代表这样，当你不能开始
transaction I don't know when you're
我不知道你什么时候交易
gonna send the packet across the network
将通过网络发送数据包
to actually begin a transaction but as
实际开始交易，但是
soon as you've done that let me know
一旦完成，就让我知道
that'll release and I'll go and execute
那会释放，我会去执行
some of the things that come after that
之后发生的一些事情
this is where things get really
这才是真正的地方
interesting for developers so once you
对开发人员很有趣，所以一旦您
have a statement and batch looks almost
有一个声明，批处理看起来几乎
exactly like this we're just not going
就像这样，我们只是不去
to talk about it because the api's are
谈论它，因为api是
so darn similar to one another but this
所以该死的彼此相似
gives you the idea that you can now bind
让您可以立即绑定
data right you can bind by some sort of
您可以通过某种方式绑定的数据权利
identifier we're going to talk about
我们将要讨论的标识符
this in some of the examples coming up
在一些即将出现的例子中
but one of the other sort of minor
但是另一种未成年人
design principles that we've chosen to
我们选择的设计原则
do is basically to say very little of
基本上是说很少
SQL is actually portable between
SQL实际上是可移植的
databases certainly there's you know
数据库肯定有你知道
sort of an ANSI SQL dialect that you can
您可以使用的一种ANSI SQL方言
use but if you ever take a look at what
使用，但如果您看一下
happens inside of something like
发生在像
hibernate or Eclipse link they really
冬眠或Eclipse链接他们真的
really heavily use dialects that allow
真的大量使用方言
them to write SQL statements that are
他们写的SQL语句是
optimized for Postgres for Oracle for
针对Postgres for Oracle进行了优化
db2 and so we said realistically that
db2，所以我们现实地说
sort of the tools that were aiming for
旨在针对的工具
tools that will have an understanding of
可以理解的工具
the dialects of the databases that
数据库的方言
they're actually connecting to so
他们实际上是在连接
whatever their identifier czar so in
无论他们的标识符沙皇在
Postgres its dollar one right dollar two
Postgres其美元一正确的美元二
dollar three is how Postgres puts
Postgres所说的三美元
they're sort of bind markers in place
它们是适当的绑定标记
but if you take a look at something like
但是如果你看看像
Microsoft sequel they use named bind
Microsoft续集，他们使用命名绑定
parameters like they're the @ sign with
像它们是@符号的参数
a name that follows it and all of the
紧随其后的名称以及所有
other databases have sort of native ways
其他数据库具有本机方式
of binding the Oracles colon name
甲骨文冒号名称的绑定
possibly spend a long time so I've
可能会花很长时间，所以我已经
actually looked at the Oracle the Oracle
实际上看了Oracle
syntax directly we want you to be able
直接语法，我们希望您能够
to say okay I've written an SQL
说好吧我已经写了一个SQL
statement I want to bind to that
我想绑定到该声明
particular identifier alternately you
特定标识符交替出现
could simply bind to positional right
可以简单地绑定到位置权
this is really useful as special
这真的很特别
in the case of of tooling this idea I
在使用这个想法的情况下，我
went to bind to the zero with bind
去用bind绑定到零
marker the first mine Margaret second
标记第一个地雷玛格丽特第二个
bind marker we did make the decision to
绑定标记，我们确实决定
somewhat break compatibility with JDBC
破坏了与JDBC的兼容性
not a big deal nothing's compatible with
没什么大不了的
JDBC in this project but go with zero
此项目中的JDBC，但为零
indexed positional binding as well and
索引位置绑定以及
then eventually once you've done all the
然后最终，一旦您完成所有
binding you'll sort of add this as a row
绑定，您将其添加为一行
we'll talk about sort of how
我们将讨论如何
preparedstatement batching works using
准备的语句批处理工作使用
add you can opt whether or not to return
添加您可以选择是否返回
generated values if you're accessing a
如果您正在访问一个生成的值
database that might create IDs
可能创建ID的数据库
automatically for you and then
自动为您，然后
eventually you're gonna call execute and
最终，您将调用执行，
execute once again says I don't know
再次执行说我不知道
when you're gonna send this query when
当您要发送此查询时
you're gonna send all of this data that
您将发送所有这些数据，
you bound to it to the database but once
您将其绑定到数据库，但是一次
you've done it please hand me back a
你已经做到了，请把我交回来
result or in the case of a multi
结果或在多个情况下
statement kind of behavior hand me back
陈述行为使我退缩
a stream of results for each thing that
每件事的结果流
you did on my behalf the result then
你代表我做了结果
gives me the ability to find out the
让我有能力找出
number of rows that were updated really
实际更新的行数
common for doing an insert or an update
进行插入或更新的常用方法
and then and this is the big deal all
然后这就是所有的大事
the only other thing is going to give
唯一的另一件事就是要付出
you the ability to do again really
你真的有能力再做一次
really simple is given a row in its
真的很简单
metadata transform that transform it to
元数据转换将其转换为
a publisher of tea so basically take
茶的出版商，所以基本上
this row and some information about this
此行以及有关此的一些信息
row and map it into an object turn it
行并将其映射为对象将其旋转
into a string turn it into an integer or
转换为字符串将其转换为整数或
something like that and then publish
像这样，然后发布
that back to me and I will start getting
回到我身上，我将开始变得
a stream of those for each individual
每个人的源头
rows the row itself really really simple
行本身真的真的很简单
API on it just allows you to get an
上面的API仅允许您获取
object get a column by its identifier
对象通过其标识符获取列
and potentially hint to the driver what
并可能向驾驶员暗示
type you'd like it to return for you so
输入您想要它返回的内容，以便
what does this look like when we
当我们看到这是什么样子
actually write some code right so what
实际写一些代码对吧
we're looking at here is taking that
我们正在看这里
connection factory creating a new
连接工厂创建一个新的
connection from it and at some point in
从它和某处的连接
the future we're going to be given that
未来，我们将被赋予
connection in our particular case here
在我们特定情况下的连接
we're calling something called flat map
我们称其为平面图
many if you're familiar with project
很多，如果您熟悉项目
reactors
反应堆
so we don't depend on project reactor at
所以我们不依赖于
the SPI level but realistically all of
SPI级别，但实际上所有
the implementations need a reactive
实现需要反应
framework behind the scenes and so the
幕后的框架等等
reactive framework most everybody is
每个人都是反应式框架
using on the spring side of the house is
在房子的Spring 侧使用的是
going to be project reactor and it makes
将成为项目反应堆，它使
a differentiator between this idea of a
这种想法之间的区别
flux which is a stream of elements from
通量是元素流
0 to n elements and a mono 0 to 1
0至n个元素和单声道0至1
elements the publisher doesn't have this
发布者没有的元素
idea right publisher basically says it's
想法权发布者基本上说这是
0 to n elements but we found
0至n个元素，但我们发现
experimentally or you know sort of in
实验性的，或者你知道
practice when talking to developers that
与开发人员交谈时练习
this idea of saying well if you're only
如果你只是说好话的想法
going to get back one that's actually a
要取回一个实际上是
really interesting thing right we want
我们想要的是非常有趣的事情
to have a first-class type of a
具有一流的
first-class set of operations on it so
一流的操作就可以了
the connection factory in this case
在这种情况下，连接工厂
creates one a mono of that connection
创建一个该连接的单声道
and then we want to flatmap that to many
然后我们想将其平面映射到许多
why do we want to flatten out to many
我们为什么要讨价还价
effectively what this says is I want you
实际上这是我要你的意思
to take this one thing and turn it into
把这件事变成它
n things so we take the connection we
n件事，所以我们建立了联系
create a statement in this case select
在这种情况下创建一个语句选择
value from test and we execute it and
测试的价值，我们执行
the thing that comes back for us is the
对我们来说回来的是
result we results map it so that
结果我们将结果映射为
basically says for each row that comes
基本上说到每一行
back I want you to go get me the value
返回我要你去给我​​带来价值
from there and internally each database
从那里以及内部的每个数据库
driver implementation each artoo DBC
每个artoo DBC的驱动程序实现
implementation has the opportunity to do
实施有机会做
what it once you've not given it a whole
一旦你没有给它一个整体
lot of thing a whole lot of information
很多东西很多信息
about what you want but you know
关于你想要什么，但是你知道
database drivers typically know right
数据库驱动程序通常知道正确
you put something in as an int for and
您将某些内容作为int
Postgres it knows it needs to come back
Postgres它知道需要回来
to send integer you put something in as
发送整数，您将某些内容放入
an INT 8 you know it needs to come back
一个INT 8，你知道它需要回来
is along you put something in as a VAR
跟着你把一些东西作为VAR
car well that's a little bit more
好车，还有一点
interesting right so in addition to this
有趣的权利，所以除了这个
you might do just a slight modification
您可能会做一点修改
saying now I want you to hand me back a
现在说我要你把我交还
string right I'm sure that they'll be so
正确的字符串，我相信他们会这样
in our implementations there are sort of
在我们的实现中，
precedence rules but realistically you
优先规则，但实际上是
want to come back and say okay I want
想回来说好，我想
you to return me a string and what
你还给我一个字符串，还有什么
effectively comes out of this you can
有效地从中可以
see sort of at the top is this values
看到顶部是这个值
publisher it says now I have a stream of
发布者说现在我有一个
each one of those values I'm no longer
这些价值中的每一个我都不再
dealing with you know database
处理你知道的数据库
connections or anything like that
连接或类似的东西
the thing that's handed to me is 0 to n
交给我的东西是0到n
strings that correspond to the value
对应于值的字符串
column and each row that will arrive to
列和将到达的每一行
me at some point in the future that I
我在将来的某个时候
don't really know what it is on some
真的不知道那是什么
thread I don't know what thread it's
线程我不知道它是什么线程
going to be on and when it's done it
将要进行的时间以及完成的时间
will either send me an error saying
要么给我发一个错误说
something has gone wrong here or it will
这里出了点问题，否则会
send me a completion stage saying I'm
给我一个完成阶段，告诉我
done sending you data you can stop
完成向您发送数据后，您可以停止
caring about it from that particular
从特定的角度来关心它
point so what does it look like to use
点，那么它看起来像什么
this API to insert data instead once
此API一次插入数据
again we've got our connection factory
再次，我们有我们的连接工厂
create we do another flat map many and
创建我们做另一幅平面图，很多
we call connection create statement
我们称连接创建语句
insert into test values dollar one
插入测试值一美元
dollar two as I said before we've made
正如我之前说过的，两美元
sort of the the the decision to stick to
坚持的决定
native bind parameters for each one of
每个的本地绑定参数
these databases so in this particular
这些数据库，所以在这个特定的
case I in in addition to leading R to
情况I除了将R引向
DBC as a whole I'm also the lead of the
总体而言，DBC我也是
Postgres implementation of RTD BC there
那里的RTD BC的Postgres实现
we'll talk about some of the other
我们将讨论其他一些
implementations that I don't actually
我实际上不是的实现
lead as well but this is where it gets
以及铅，但这就是它的来源
really interesting because for those of
真的很有趣，因为对于那些
you who have sort of unfortunate
那些不幸的人
encyclopedia college at the JDBC API
JDBC API的百科全书学院
you'll remember back to the API we have
您会记得我们拥有的API
this idea of statements yes but we also
这种说法的想法是的，但我们也
have this idea of three different kinds
有三种不同的想法
of statements there's a statement
声明中有一个声明
there's a prepared statement there's a
有一个准备好的声明，有一个
callable statement and if any of you can
可收回的陈述，如果你们可以的话
tell me the difference between those
告诉我这些之间的区别
three and exactly when you're supposed
三，确切地说，当你应该
to use all of them you are much better
使用所有这些，你会更好
developer than I will ever be the thing
开发人员比我将永远成为事物
was if you ever took a look at the
如果你曾经看过
implementations of these inside of
这些在内部的实现
inside of the JDBC drivers they all
在JDBC驱动程序内部
delegate it back to a single way that
将其委托给单一方式
you communicate with the database over
您通过数据库与数据库进行通信
the wire protocol all databases these
有线协议所有这些数据库
days expect you to send something that
几天希望您发送一些
optionally has some bind markers inside
可以选择在其中包含一些绑定标记
of it potentially send a bunch of frames
它可能会发送一堆帧
to talk about how you bound data to all
谈论如何将数据绑定到所有人
that thing and then returns they all
那件事，然后将它们全部归还
treat every single invocation exactly
准确地对待每个调用
the same so we said if that's the truth
一样，所以我们说如果是真的
let's not keep all that crufty multiple
让我们不要保留所有繁琐的倍数
different kinds of statements what we
不同类型的陈述
instead want is a single kind of
相反，想要的只是一种
statement create statement where we bind
声明我们绑定的地方的声明
some stuff to it and then you'll notice
一些东西，然后你会注意到
effectively what we're doing is prepared
有效地准备我们正在做的事情
statement batching
语句批处理
you do a bind to dollar one I want to
你想绑定一美元，我想
bind the number 100 then to bind to
绑定数字100然后绑定到
dollar two and want to bind the number
美元二，想要绑定数字
200 this is effectively multiple
200这实际上是倍数
positions but in a single insert
位置，但一次插入
statement now at this point you can call
现在就可以声明
execute if you only wanted to do one of
如果您只想执行以下一项操作，请执行
these that's fine it sort of implicitly
这些很好，隐含地
says okay this must be the road that you
说好吧，这一定是你的路
wanted to insert but we also have the
想插入，但我们也有
ability to say well it's actually really
说的能力实际上是真的
efficient for most of these databases if
对于大多数这些数据库，如果有效
what you do is you send the SQL query
您要做的就是发送SQL查询
and then just send effectively a table
然后有效地发送一张桌子
of data that follows it so what we want
跟随它的数据，所以我们想要
to do is say add basically this is a
要做的是说基本上添加这是一个
carriage return right this says okay I'm
回车，这说好，我是
done doing all of the bindings that we
完成了我们所有的绑定
need to do let me snap it back to the
需要做的是让我将其捕捉回
beginning and let me do another row of
开始，让我再做一排
bindings and you have the ability to
绑定，您就有能力
call a defectively as many times as
多次拨打次品
you'd like to add as many rows as you
您想添加尽可能多的行
want and then eventually at some point
想要，然后最终在某个时候
in the future you'll call execute again
将来您会再次调用执行
it's sort of optional on the last one
在最后一个上有点可选
because we assume you you mean to start
因为我们假设您是要开始
a new line effectively or you were
有效地换一条新线，或者你曾经
effectively ending the road that you're
有效地结束了你的路
on like that carriage return and it will
像回车一样
block send all of that data to a
阻止将所有数据发送到
database in a really really efficient
真正高效的数据库
way we'll notice this time when it comes
这次我们会注意到的方式
around we haven't done anything with the
周围我们没有做任何事情
data so we just end up with a publisher
数据，所以我们最终只能得到发布者
of results each one of those insert
结果的每个插入
lines has a result tied to it in all in
行在所有方面都与之相关
every reasonable database effectively
有效地建立每个合理的数据库
what that's result is going to contain
结果将包含
is the integer number of rows that you
是您的整数行数
actually inserted right so I expect to
实际上插入正确，所以我希望
basically get back a bunch of results
基本上得到一堆结果
that say 1 1 1 1 1 1 but you can
那说1 1 1 1 1 1但你可以
remember you can think of something like
记住你可以想到类似
using this to do an update with
用这个来做更新
optimistic locking for example where
乐观锁定，例如
you're only updating a particular row if
您仅在以下情况下更新特定行
the version number matches the previous
版本号与先前的版本号匹配
version number and then you can expect
版本号，然后您可以期待
was one row updated was zero rows
是更新的一行是零行
updated do I need to attempt to to have
更新后我是否需要尝试拥有
another go with this so a very common
另一个与此很常见
pattern especially inside of ORM is this
尤其是在ORM内部的模式是
idea of optimistic locking and that's
乐观锁定的想法，那就是
all supported from here now let's take a
现在从这里获得所有支持
look at that same prepared insert and
看一下相同的准备插入
what it means to add transactions so
这样添加交易意味着什么
miracle of miracles at all
奇迹的奇迹
we have transactionality this was not a
我们有交易能力，这不是
foregone can
放弃可以
youjin this whole thing where you don't
整个这件事你都不会
actually understand when something is
真正了解什么时候是
executed and so we're in the flow you
被执行，所以我们在你的流程中
can actually send the frame to begin a
可以实际发送框架开始
transaction or commit the transaction
交易或提交交易
roll it back but we did finally get
回滚，但我们终于得到了
there once again we have a flat map many
那里又有一张平面图
we take the connection and we call begin
我们建立连接，我们开始
transaction with that connection then
然后与该连接进行交易
from there if you remember begin
从那里开始，如果您还记得开始的话
transaction does a number a publisher
交易对发行人有影响
void right so it says okay now I'm done
无效吧，所以说好了，我完成了
then I want to take that and say create
然后我想接受并说创造
a statement insert a couple rows into it
一条语句在其中插入几行
and then I do this thing that's called
然后我做这个被称为
delay until you really have to
延迟直到您真的必须
understand reactor I've been using it a
了解反应堆，我一直在使用它
lot to understand that basically says
很多要理解的基本上是说
hold on to the data that happened before
保留之前发生的数据
this commit the transaction and let all
提交交易，让所有
of that data go through but what happens
的数据通过，但会发生什么
if there's an error right what if one of
如果有错误，如果其中之一
the insertions is onto a road that
插入物在一条道路上
already exists so you passin annulled it
已经存在，所以您将其废除
shouldn't actually be there right an
实际上不应该在那里
error could come back at any time
错误随时可能再次出现
so it's possible we never actually call
所以有可能我们从未真正致电
con commit transaction instead have to
确认交易而不是必须
call on error resume roll back the
调用错误恢复简历回滚
transaction but can't lose the error so
交易但不能丢失错误，因此
we then have to send off the mono error
然后，我们必须发送单声道错误
with the the exception that was in it
除了其中的例外
before and now all of a sudden you start
以前，现在突然之间，您开始
looking at this and you're going that is
看着这个，你要去的是
not code that I want to write right and
不是我想写的代码，
what you actually end up seeing is for
您最终看到的是为了
those of you who can remember any of
那些谁能记住任何
your JDBC stuff right what we're
您的JDBC东西对我们而言
actually talking about that that pattern
实际上在谈论那种模式
at the end there right this delay until
最后有这个延迟，直到
commit transaction on error resumed roll
在错误恢复卷上提交事务
back the transaction then forward the
退回交易，然后转发
air on this is try catch finally try
空气这是尝试赶上最后尝试
cache the way you were all supposed to
缓存所有人的方式
you JDBC in a raw manner and we all
JDBC的原始方式，我们所有人
screwed it up like I guarantee starting
像我保证开始一样搞砸了
my career the first half dozen bugs I
我的职业生涯前六个漏洞
wrote we're because I didn't do try
写道我们是因为我没有尝试
catch finally try catch so it's usable
抓住最后尝试抓住，所以它是可用的
right it's effectively taking us back to
对，这有效地带我们回到了
where we were when JDBC first start out
JDBC刚开始时的位置
very verbose prone to errors it's only a
非常冗长，容易出错，只是
matter of time so you forget you know to
时间的问题，所以你忘了知道
handle the error and do the rollback
处理错误并进行回滚
there but remember our focus right our
在那里，但要记住我们的专注
focus is that the driver SPI contains
重点是驱动程序SPI包含
the minimal set of operations that are
最小的一组操作
implementation specific and nothing
具体实施，一无所获
before right it means that we're
在正确之前，这意味着我们
actually designing for this to look
实际设计为此看起来
really bad and be really difficult to
真的很糟糕，很难
use and that seems super crazy right but
使用，这似乎超级疯狂吧，但是
what we need is a humane client a peon
我们需要的是人道的客户牡丹
you shouldn't ever use this code what we
您不应该使用此代码
need is a bunch of humane clients a
需要的是一群人道的客户
peons so as a demonstration of what you
牡丹，作为你的示范
might do with our two DBC I wrote a
可能与我们两个DBC有关
project called r2 DBC client and it's
名为r2 DBC客户端的项目，
fundamentally sort of inspired a ripoff
从根本上启发了窃取
of JD bi it was never supposed to sort
JD bi的故事从来都不应该排序
of go into production or anything like
投入生产或类似
that but if you're familiar with JD bi
那，但如果您熟悉JD bi
you'll see a lot of the same kinds of
您会看到很多相同类型的
things this idea that we have an r2 DBC
这个想法，我们有一个r2 DBC
object I don't know what exactly what
对象我不知道到底是什么
that is we say with a handle handle is
那就是说带手柄的手柄是
basically just sort of a wrapper around
基本上只是一个包装
connection and a whole bunch of other
连接和一大堆其他
state and automated mappers and things
状态和自动映射器及事物
like that and we're gonna do something
那样，我们要做一些事情
that's a bit more sort of fluent right
比较流利吧
it's not create statement with a
它不是带有
specific kind of thing instead we're
某种特定的东西相反，我们是
just gonna say select and we have to put
只是要说选择，我们必须把
a select style statement in there and
在其中选择样式声明，然后
what happens is when we come back and we
发生的事情是当我们回来时，我们
do some sort of mapping notice this map
做某种映射注意此图
row we don't map row and metadata most
行，我们最多不映射行和元数据
of the time nobody cares right like
那个时候没人在意
think of how you actually use JDBC how
想一想您实际使用JDBC的方式
you access a database if I'm gonna
您访问数据库，如果我要
select value from test I know it's a
从测试中选择值，我知道这是一个
string right like I don't need to
正确的字符串，就像我不需要
inspect any metadata to find out tooling
检查任何元数据以找出工具
might need to but realistically me as an
可能需要但实际上我是
application developer I know what that
应用程序开发人员我知道那是什么
column is going to be you could always
专栏将成为你永远可以
fall back to the raw our JDBC API but
回到原始的JDBC API，但
this is a humane API right this is what
这是一个人性化的API，这就是
are the ways most people are actually
是大多数人实际使用的方式
gonna do this and you'll even notice
要这样做，你甚至会注意到
from there that we actually return to
从那里，我们实际上回到
flux from this right we're in the r2 DBC
来自此权利的流量，我们在r2 DBC中
api focuses very strongly on being
api非常重视
completely neutral using the reactive
使用反应性完全中性
streams API you can imagine a future
流API，您可以想象未来
beyond Java 9 when everybody's upgraded
每个人都升级后，超越Java 9
to 11 or further we might switch on to
到11或更远，我们可能会打开
flow or something like that this idea
流动或类似的想法
that we want to stick to something
我们想要坚持的东西
completely neutral but when we get to
完全中立，但是当我们
humane api's we can be opinionated we
人道的api的我们可以认为我们
can say you know most spring users
可以说您知道大多数 Spring 用户
really are using reactor maybe we should
真的在使用反应堆，也许我们应该
return fluxes and monos rather than raw
返回通量和单声道而不是原始
publishers all right maybe you're you
出版商好吧，也许你就是你
know the
知道
the Juke implementer and you're more of
Juke实施者，您将更加
an RX Java to kind of an maybe you
RX Java之类的
return singles and flowable z-- I think
返回单身和可流动的z-我认为
what they're called you can have those
他们叫什么，你可以拥有那些
kind of opinions in this client and
该客户的意见和
really work with the teams that are your
与您的团队真正合作
customers what does the prepared insert
客户准备好的插入物是什么
actually look like excuse me again with
看起来又像是对不起我
handle maybe we'll do a create update
处理也许我们会创建一个更新
this time we do binding to the execution
这次我们绑定执行
you'll notice we haven't had to do a
您会注意到我们不必做
mapping that sort of pulls out the the
映射那种拉出
number of rows or anything like that
行数之类的
actually I should probably be flux ated
其实我应该被吃掉了
your amount of flux string it was typing
您输入的助焊剂字符串量
bit late last night and it just returns
昨晚有点晚，它只是返回
the updated rows
更新的行
realistically none of us actually look
实际上我们当中没有一个人看起来
at the number of rows to come back but
在要返回的行数上
let's say that's probably what you
假设这可能就是你
wanted to do if you were using a client
想使用客户端来做
like this and now you see what a client
这样，现在您看到了一个客户
can give you right let's take a look
可以给你正确的，让我们看一下
back this is what the insert looked like
后面是插入物的样子
you'll notice where it says r2 DBC with
您会注意到其中说r2 DBC的位置
handle here but now if we wanted to go
在这里处理，但现在如果我们想去
into a transaction it's very very simple
交易非常简单
right just change to a little word but
正确的只是一个小词，但
otherwise it looks exactly the same
否则看起来完全一样
because internally you expect a client
因为在内部您希望有一个客户
to implement that try catch finally try
实施尝试赶上最后尝试
catch kind of behavior the delay until
捕捉行为延迟到
on error resume then mono error kind of
错误恢复，然后出现单声道错误
behavior you can hide all that and a
行为，您可以隐藏所有这些和
user just does something really really
用户只是真正地做某事
simple but these are all sort of JD bi
很简单，但是都是JD bi
inspired flew into api's you know sort
灵感飞到api的你知道排序
of what I started trying to do as an
我开始尝试做的
example we can go further than that
例如，我们可以走得更远
right what if you're a spring data user
对，如果您是spring数据用户怎么办
already and you like a lot of the api's
已经并且您喜欢很多api的
the spring data gives you well they can
spring data 可以使您满意
build on top of this r2 DBC API that's
建立在该r2 DBC API之上
totally inhumane but is really what they
完全不人道，但实际上是他们
want to do because they need to do so
想要这样做，因为他们需要这样做
much programmatic behavior so they've
程序性行为很多，所以他们已经
created in the spring data RTD BC
在 spring data RTD BC中创建
project this database client thing takes
投影此数据库客户端的内容
one of our connection factories from RTD
RTD我们的连接工厂之一
BC and it allows you to say execute some
公元前，它允许您说执行一些
SQL binding and this particular case one
SQL绑定和这种特殊情况之一
of the really great things about it is
真正伟大的事情是
the spring data RTD BC project is all in
spring data RTD BC项目全在
on named bindings like no more of this
在命名绑定上不再像这样
question marks no more of this dollar
问不了这美元
one
一
they will do the dialect work internally
他们将在内部进行方言工作
to guarantee that you always use a
以确保您始终使用
really really descriptive SQL expression
真的很描述性的SQL表达式
right you should always be saying : name
对，你应该一直在说：名字
you should always be you know having
你应该永远是你知道
some sort of contextual thing there and
那里的某种情境事物
so now you bind by name for a particular
所以现在您按名称绑定特定的
value you tell it when you want to do
当你想做时告诉你的价值
that selection I want as the data comes
我想要的选择数据
out please automatically map it back to
请自动将其映射回
a person for me go fetch all of those as
我一个人去拿所有这些
you go and so now it's not quite JPA
你去，所以现在还不算JPA
right but it does do a little bit of a
是的，但是确实有点
warming in a limited way really really
真的以有限的方式变暖
flexible great great choice if you're
灵活的绝佳选择，如果您
into flew into api's like that I skew
像我歪一样飞进api
the other way quite a bit I'm a huge fan
反过来说，我很喜欢
personally of spring data repositories
亲自从Spring数据存储库
instead spring data repositories are
相反，Spring数据存储库是
great for me because I get to write a
对我来说很棒，因为我可以写一个
bunch of you know sort of very simple
你们知道的很简单
method declarations in an interface and
接口中的方法声明和
I allow the really smart team behind the
我允许真正聪​​明的团队
spring data so we got how to turn that
Spring 的数据，所以我们得到了如何扭转
into an SQL query how to turn that into
到SQL查询如何将其变成
the mappings that need to be done in our
我们需要完成的映射
particular case here in the current
当前的特殊情况
release because we aren't sort of
释放，因为我们不是
building on top of an ORM that has a
建立在具有
bunch of schema information in it I'm
一堆模式信息
still required to write the query but we
仍然需要编写查询，但是我们
get automatic mapping between say named
获得说出的名字之间的自动映射
parameters and the name parameter
参数和名称参数
between those two we get a flux of
在这两者之间，我们得到了
customers back so it automatically knows
客户回去，以便它自动知道
rather than having to describe here that
而不是在这里描述
I want you to return these rows as a
我希望您将这些行作为
person it knows hey I can just inspect
知道的人嘿，我可以检查
this and know that you want a stream of
这个，知道你想要一个
customers to come back gives us the
顾客回来给我们
ability to do that repository find by
执行该存储库的能力
last name and then for each one of those
姓，然后每个
do something in this case just printing
在这种情况下只需打印即可
out what the first name was for each one
找出每个人的名字
of those Matthews people so I find that
这些马修斯人中，所以我发现
you know sort of more to my style but
你对我的风格了解更多，但
the key takeaway here is you don't have
这里的关键要点是你没有
to decide between like I don't have to
决定之间，就像我不必
decide as you know someone involved in
如您所知，决定参与其中
the RTD BC project we want all of those
RTD BC项目，我们希望所有这些
opportunities to be available to every
每个人都有机会
single one of the developers so we're
一个开发人员之一，所以我们
going to take a look now at some of the
现在来看看一些
other features that are 2d BC does
公元前2d的其他功能
beyond just sort of usage of it because
不仅仅是它的用途，因为
it turns out that it's
原来是
just you know using a client API or
只要您知道使用客户端API或
using the the driver spi it's really
使用驱动程序spi确实
there are a bunch of other things around
周围还有很多其他事情
using a database driver that are really
使用真正的数据库驱动程序
interesting so one of the big ones is
有趣，所以其中之一是
connection URLs if you don't know
连接网址（如果您不知道）
connection URL parsing in java is
java中的连接URL解析是
actually quite problematic for example
例如，实际上是有问题的
the URI class doesn't have a
URI类没有
standardized way in Java of parsing
Java解析中的标准化方法
query parameters
查询参数
you'd think that's a really important
你会认为这是非常重要的
bit know spring has one database drivers
有点知道spring有一个数据库驱动程序
have other implementations there is no
有其他实现没有
common way of doing it because everybody
通用的方式，因为每个人
do it exactly to the spec especially
严格按照规范进行
since the URI spec that's sort of right
因为URI规范是正确的
end where the query parameters are
结束查询参数所在的位置
really sketchy really sketchy it's it's
真的很粗略真的很粗略
difficult to do right so one of the
很难做到正确，所以其中之一
things we've opted to do here is saying
我们选择在这里做的事情是说
passing around opaque URLs is really
传递不透明的URL确实是
important to a lot of database people I
对于很多数据库人来说，我都很重要
come from as I said the Cloud Foundry
来自我所说的Cloud Foundry
side which means we do a lot of this
这意味着我们要做很多
bind to service to your application your
绑定到您的应用程序服务
environment has a URL have spring boot
环境中有一个URL有spring boot
applications automatically use that URL
应用程序自动使用该URL
users never ever see what it is where
用户永远不会看到它在哪里
the information it contains so we know
它包含的信息，所以我们知道
it's a good way to be a really dense
这是成为一个真正密集的好方法
communication of information but we
信息交流，但我们
don't want sort of the Wild West the way
不想像狂野西部那样
we have in JDBC today so what we've
我们今天在JDBC中拥有
chosen to do is move that right move the
选择要做的是向右移动
parsing of this URL into the
将该网址解析为
specification itself right not what you
规范本身对不对
do with the pieces of it but we'll say
做它的碎片，但我们会说
take that top URL there are two DB CS
拿那个顶级URL有两个DB CS
saying we want to do this with a TLS
说我们想用TLS做到这一点
encrypted or two DB C connection to
加密或两个DB C连接
Postgres at local host port 5432 with a
Postgres在 localhost 端口5432上带有
particular database name in this case
在这种情况下，特定的数据库名称
db2 and with some query parameters
db2并带有一些查询参数
schema test behind the scenes there is a
幕后的模式测试
single implementation inside the spec
规范内的单一实现
that parses this into basically a bunch
基本上将其解析为一堆
of tokens says here's the driver name
的令牌说这是驱动程序名称
here's the host name here's the port
这是主机名这是端口
name here is some random thing called
这里的名字叫一些随机的东西
schema that I don't know what it is and
我不知道它是什么的模式
I'm gonna hand it to you database driver
我要交给你数据库驱动程序
and you get to decide how to interpret
然后你决定如何解释
it not how to parse it out of the URL
它不是如何从URL中解析它
where everybody's doing it differently
每个人都在做不同的事情
but you do get to decide what it means
但是你一定要决定是什么意思
to you
给你
and one of the really cool side effects
和非常酷的副作用之一
of this is that means that we then can
这就是说我们可以
do some really interesting decoration
做一些非常有趣的装饰
wrapping right when it comes time to do
要做的时候正确包装
pooling we don't have to change sort of
集中我们不必改变
the fundamental bits of the URL right
正确的URL基本位
still says Postgres localized 54 32 DB
仍然说Postgres本地化了54 32 DB
schema equals test but by prepending
架构等于测试，但前提是
Postgres and saying i also want you to
Postgres说我也要你
do pooling and i want the pool size as
做池，我希望池大小为
we put there on a query parameter to be
我们放在一个查询参数上
for now we sort of have this chain of
现在，我们有点像
execution where we go and look up and we
执行，我们去那里查找，我们
see this sort of at the end we call
最后，我们称这种情况为
connection factories passing something
连接工厂传递一些东西
in and internally we use say the service
在内部，我们使用说服务
loader support and java to go find out
加载程序支持和Java去了解
who in the r2 DBC world will handle pool
r2 DBC世界中的谁将处理池
and that pool knows how to configure
而且该池知道如何配置
reactor pool make sure the size is
反应池确保尺寸为
exactly four then it takes all the
恰好四个然后
configuration that it didn't care about
它不在乎的配置
what concrete database driver it was
它是什么具体的数据库驱动程序
what host port database and other
什么主机端口数据库等
parameters go in there and it's gonna
参数进入那里，它将
just delegate those back into the system
只是将那些委托给系统
and allow a different database driver
并允许使用其他数据库驱动程序
than to interpret that and wrap it
而不是解释并包装它
around there and this is basically
那里，这基本上是
unending right we could wrap this we're
没完没了的权利，我们可以把它包装起来
gonna talk a little bit in a second
一秒钟要谈一点
about observability we can wrap this in
关于可观察性，我们可以将其包装在
some sort of observability it could be
某种可观察性
our two DB c colon micrometer colon pool
我们的两个DB C结肠测微计结肠池
colon Postgres and now of a sudden you
冒号Postgres，现在突然之间
get a really predictable buildable uri
获得一个真正可预测的可构建uri
that can that is parsed uniformly but
那可以被统一解析，但是
still allows the flexibility of a bunch
仍然允许一堆的灵活性
of different implementations to use it
使用它的不同实现
so what can you do today
那你今天能做什么
earlier this week I must have been
这周早些时候我一定是
Monday actually we released 0.8.0 m8 we
星期一我们实际上发布了0.8.0 m8
have a goal to do an RC one in August
有一个目标是在八月份做一个RC
maybe and a release in October we're
也许和十月发布的
going to take this to a GA but one of
打算把它带到GA，但其中之一
the things we're trying to communicate
我们试图传达的东西
here is by choosing zero eight zero we
这是通过选择零八零我们
don't think the spec is done right we
不要认为规范做对了
think that there are probably places
认为可能有地方
where we've missed some stuff where we
我们错过了一些东西
want client drivers to come in and say
希望客户司机进来并说
hey I need another API or a database
嘿，我需要其他API或数据库
driver to come in and say this isn't
司机进来说这不是
actually defined concretely enough so
实际上定义得足够具体
there is still room for some change
仍有改变的空间
but with a 0-8 release right what we're
但是0-8版本就可以了
indicating to those same vendors and to
向那些相同的供应商和
you as customers is this is a thing you
作为客户，这是你的事
should actually start using production I
实际上应该开始使用生产我
don't know maybe not but we think that
不知道也许不是，但我们认为
this is good we think it's very solid we
这很好，我们认为它非常扎实
think that you can run workloads on top
认为您可以在顶部运行工作负载
of it but you should expect some change
它，但你应该期待一些改变
in the future so if you're very
在未来，所以如果你非常
conservative probably not a good idea to
保守可能不是一个好主意
start looking at it but it allows other
开始看它，但它允许其他
vendors to start looking at it inside of
供应商开始在内部查看它
the zero 8 m8 release we already have
我们已经拥有的零8 m8版本
driver implementations for h2 for
H2的驱动程序实现
testing Microsoft sequel server Postgres
测试Microsoft续集服务器Postgres
server the community has actually
社区实际拥有的服务器
contributed to different my sequel
为我的续集做出了贡献
implementations ja sync SQL which is a
实现ja sync SQL这是一个
my sequel driver implemented totally in
我的续集驱动程序完全在
Kotlin took that driver took an r2 DBC
Kotlin接了那位驾驶员，让他驾驶了r2 DBC
interface and sort of glued it onto the
接口并将其粘到
side works really really well and then
方面真的很好，然后
there's another from-scratch
还有另一个从头开始
implementation called RTD DC my sequel
称为RTD DC的实现
and each one of these has extensive
并且每一个都有广泛的
support already today it deals with
今天已经支持
batching extensive type conversion so
批量扩展类型转换，因此
for example the RTD bc spec defines
例如RTD bc规范定义
about two dozen types that you should
您应该选择大约两种类型
always be able to convert from and to
始终能够从和转换为
and then each implementation is allowed
然后允许每个实现
to extend on that if they want to we
如果他们愿意，可以继续
have full blob and CLOB supports and you
有完整的Blob和CLOB支持，您
can think about this wow this is a
可以考虑一下，哇，这是一个
really really great sort of use case for
真的是非常好的用例
reactive programming this idea that I
反应性编程这个想法，我
can request request a gigabyte of data
可以请求请求一个千兆字节的数据
from my database and it'll only stream
从我的数据库中，它只会流
in at the rate that I can consume it we
以我可以消费的速度
have save points transactions database
有保存点交易数据库
specific features so Postgres for
特定功能，因此Postgres用于
example has a pub sub kind of thing that
例子中有一个pub sub的东西
we can implement their service loader
我们可以实现他们的服务加载器
driver discovery for all these and
所有这些的驱动程序发现和
support for our connection URLs but it
支持我们的连接URL，但它
goes even beyond that right it's not
甚至超越了那个权利
just sufficient for you to you know have
足以让您知道
a couple of driver implementations we've
我们已经完成了一些驱动程序实现
got a very robust and definitely getting
有一个非常强大的，肯定会
better not do to my work certainly one
最好不要对我的工作做一个
of the other members of the team is
团队其他成员中的
really really diligent about this
真的很勤奋
defining a true specification a textual
定义一个真正的规范文本
thing to finding all the rules so if you
找到所有规则的事情，如果
wanted to go out and do an
想出去做一个
implementation you know what you're
实现你知道你是什么
aiming for we have connection pooling so
瞄准我们有连接池，所以
pooling in a reactive non walking async
在反应性非步行异步中池化
kind of environments incredibly
令人难以置信的环境
difficult but the project reactor team
困难但项目反应堆小组
has been working hard on it for months
几个月来一直在努力
and months and months and they've really
和几个月又几个月，他们真的
cracked it now we have sort of this
破解它，我们已经有了这个
generic object pool that anybody can use
任何人都可以使用的通用对象池
but most importantly I can use for
但最重要的是我可以用于
connection pooling because it's really
连接池，因为它确实
really important in databases we have
在我们拥有的数据库中非常重要
two out-of-the-box implementations
两种现成的实现
already spring data r2 DBC and r2 DBC
已经弹出数据r2 DBC和r2 DBC
client and as I mentioned earlier this
客户，正如我之前提到的
morning it's been really important to
早上真的很重要
the tools vendors and the Java ecosystem
工具供应商和Java生态系统
that observability be a really
可观察性是一个真正的
first-class concept
一流的概念
we'd sort of always thought about it and
我们总是会考虑
then you know sort of started talking to
那么你就知道开始和
the APM vendors we worked really really
我们真正工作过的APM供应商
closely with the data dog team
与数据狗团队紧密合作
specifically and they show to see you
具体来说，他们会来看你
know here the kind of things we just
在这里知道我们只是那种事情
can't do in JDBC and in one of sort of
在JDBC中无法做到
the the most amazing bits of serendipity
最奇妙的巧合
I've ever experienced in an open-source
我曾经在开源方面经历过
project we randomly just got an email to
项目，我们随机收到一封电子邮件
the mailing list about a guy who's it oh
关于一个男人的邮件列表哦
yeah I wrote this entire you know sort
是的，我写了这整本书，你知道
of private project in my own org and
我自己的组织中的私人项目
it's an entire proxying mechanism full
这是完整的完整代理机制
100% observability for the RTD bc spec
RTD bc规范的100％可观察性
what do you think of this and we
您对此有何看法，我们
immediately said what do we think would
马上说我们怎么想
you like to be promoted to a first you
你喜欢被提升为第一个你
know top tier project inside of our to
了解我们内部的顶级项目
DBC as part of the official thing yeah
DBC是官方的一部分
absolutely and so today is now you know
绝对，所以今天就是现在
sort of a core team member responsible
某种核心团队成员负责
for all of our observability around RTD
围绕RTD的所有可观察性
BC prophecy but you might you know we'll
卑诗省的预言，但您可能知道我们会
finish off here with a little bit why
在这里结束一点点为什么
are we doing RTD BC what is what about
我们在做RTD BC吗
the alternatives we might want to do
我们可能想做的替代方案
right so the first one is wrapping a
对，所以第一个包裹一个
jdbc in a thread pool I've alluded to
我提到的线程池中的jdbc
this a little bit JDBC is a blocking API
这一点JDBC是一个阻塞的API
it is literally impossible to turn a
从根本上讲不可能
blocking API into a non blocking API you
将API阻塞为非阻塞API
can do the reverse you can turn
可以做相反的事情，你可以转
non-blocking into blocking just fine but
非阻塞变为阻塞，但
once you have blocking the only way to
一旦您阻止了
sort of break it from a non-blocking
从非阻塞中打破它
flow is to add queuing okay queuing we
流程是添加队列，好吧，我们排队
all know how to do queues we have two
所有人都知道如何做队列，我们​​有两个
kinds of queues unbounded queues bounded
各种队列无界队列
queues an unbounded queue imagine we
排队无限制的队列想象我们
were talking a little bit earlier in the
在较早的时候说话
keynote for reactive reactive generally
反应性反应性主题演讲
things like web flux now all of a sudden
像网络流量这样的事情现在突然之间
instead of handling hundreds of
而不是处理数百个
connections or maybe thousands of
连接或数千
connections now we're handling tens of
现在我们正在处理数十个
thousands of simultaneous connections
数千个同时连接
all of which may be sitting in a queue
所有这些都可能坐在队列中
waiting to get access to J
等待访问J
BBC write a limited number of resources
英国广播公司写有限数量的资源
and when that happens work sort of under
当这种情况发生时，
high load situations maybe we want to
高负载情况下，我们可能想
take a look at a bounded queue instead
看看有界队列
bounded queues lead to blocking as soon
有限的队列导致尽快阻塞
as you fill this queue so that you don't
当您填充此队列时，您不会
exceed your heap bang right like you
像你一样超越你的堆爆炸
have a block but since you've only got
有一个障碍，但因为你只有
four threads or a thread some very small
四个线程或一个很小的线程
number of threads the next four requests
接下来的四个请求的线程数
it all go into this sort of waiting
这一切都在等待
queue basically shut down your entire
队列基本上关闭了整个
system you don't have that throughput
系统没有吞吐量
that you want so we've got a problem
您想要的，所以我们遇到了问题
there so wrapping JDBC isn't really an
所以包装JDBC并不是一个真正的
option for us instead we have to have
我们的选择，我们必须
something designed from scratch around a
从头开始设计的东西
synchronicity and to be honest there are
同步性和说实话
other specifications that are attempting
尝试的其他规格
this same kind of thing realistically
现实中这种事情
they're all in very very early stages
他们都处于非常早期的阶段
they all have a very similar design to
它们的设计都非常相似
what our 2d BC is we you know sort of
我们的二维BC是什么，我们知道
have a head start on them by maybe a
在他们身上先行一步
year or something like that but each one
一年或类似的东西，但每一年
of these typically has a small number of
这些通常有少量的
implementations typically the number is
实施方式通常为
0 or 1 but I think we are very clear in
0或1，但我认为我们非常清楚
the AR JDBC team that the future of all
AR JDBC团队认为所有人的未来
of these projects is collaboration the
这些项目是合作
markets not going to take you know
市场不会让你知道
multiple competing standards on this so
因此有多个竞争标准
realistically we will have to sort of
实际上，我们将不得不
collaborate with all these things onto a
与所有这些东西协作到一个
single standard that will eventually
单一标准，最终将
come to the Java ecosystem for this this
为此来到Java生态系统
is my safe harbor statement that has a
是我的安全港声明，其中有一个
lot of words it says what I'm about to
很多话说我要
tell you may be a complete lie by the
告诉你可能是一个完全的谎言
time it happens so what do we want to do
时间发生了，所以我们想做什么
in the future
在将来
so the key things to get us to rc1 we
所以让我们进入rc1的关键是
want to do a couple more additions
想要多做一些补充
improvements for the SPI that we know we
我们知道的SPI的改进
need to do I cannot believe this
需要做的我不敢相信
that this first bullet is on here when I
当我第一颗子弹在这里
design the API I intentionally avoided
设计我故意避免的API
stored procedure like nobody uses stored
像没有人使用存储过程一样的存储过程
procedures anymore who uses stored
谁使用存储的程序了
procedures turns out I am completely
程序证明我完全
wrong there are a lot of stored
错了，有很多存储
procedures out in the world and almost
程序遍布世界各地
all the client vendors are really clear
所有的客户供应商都非常清楚
that you must absolutely have support
你必须绝对有支持
for stored procedures so we need to go
对于存储过程，所以我们需要
and do that we also want to talk about
我们要做的就是谈论
auto commit and fetch size again driven
自动提交并再次获取大小
and this is like
这就像
the the the great synergy is a great
伟大的协同作用是伟大的
thing about working in the open source
关于在开源中工作的事情
with all of these other projects both of
与所有其他这些项目
those bullets led by Lucas editor of the
由卢卡斯（Lucas）编辑领导的子弹
the Juke project came to us and said hey
Juke项目来找我们说
I need to know whether I'm currently in
我要知道我现在是否在
an auto commit mode I need to be able to
自动提交模式，我需要能够
set the fetch size because reactor has
设置获取大小，因为反应堆有
an idea of when it goes back to the
关于何时回到
database and says send me the next date
数据库，说下次寄给我
rows send me the next hundred and
行发送给我下一百个
twenty-eight rows send me the next turn
第二十八排给我下一转
or fifty six rows it kind of has an idea
或五十六行有点想法
it's it's tuned dynamically what exactly
它是动态调整的
it can go and ask for but you can do
它可以去问，但你可以做
better if you're a database user and you
如果您是数据库用户并且您会更好
know about how much data is going to be
知道会有多少数据
sent in you can ask for a fixed number
发送来的你可以要求一个固定的号码
of rows that more matches it we also
更匹配的行数
want to see more implementations Google
希望看到更多Google实现
Cloud spanner actually has a public repo
云扳手实际上有一个公共仓库
right now where they're beginning their
现在他们开始的地方
work on db2 sa p Hana and db2 are both
Hana和db2都在db2 sap上工作
sort of taking a look at it
有点看它
investigating it as we try and round out
我们尝试进行调查时对其进行调查
the group of databases that have it and
具有它的数据库组，以及
I think what we really want to we really
我认为我们真正想要的是我们真正的
want to stress even though sort of the
想要强调即使
first three database drivers we're all
前三个数据库驱动程序都是我们
implemented internally inside of the RTD
在RTD内部实现
BC team by Spring and pivotal employees
Spring BC团队和关键员工
is that we actually prefer database
是我们实际上更喜欢数据库
vendors to own the drivers long-term I
供应商要长期拥有司机
am an unfortunate expert in the Postgres
是Postgres中的不幸专家
wire protocol but I don't know nearly as
有线协议，但我几乎不知道
much as the Postgres team actually does
和Postgres团队实际所做的一样
and so we've already engaged with for
因此，我们已经与
example the the lead of the JDBC driver
示例JDBC驱动程序的负责人
for Postgres and he is you know everyday
给Postgres，他就是你每天都知道
been there committing answering issues
在那里承诺回答问题
for us with sort of an eye towards if we
对我们而言，如果我们
get this done if this actually becomes a
如果这实际上变成一个
standard they'll take that over take it
他们会接管的
out of our hands which i think is really
从我们手中出来，我认为这是真的
really a good thing and then finally we
真的是一件好事，最后我们
also want a lot of additional clients to
也想要很多其他客户
catch a TBI mybatis all have some sort
赶上TBI mybatis都有某种
of additional support I'm taking a look
我正在寻找其他支持
at this that's you know sort of the the
在这一点上，你知道的
long-term goals it gets us to 0-8
长期目标使我们达到0-8
release and eventually 100 release so
发布并最终发布100次，因此
the final slide I'm going to leave you
最后一张幻灯片，我要离开你
with here is some resources there is an
这里有一些资源
R 2 DB cio website we have a twitter
R 2 DB cio网站我们有一个推特
we've got a cute little icon for us
我们有一个可爱的小图标给我们
github everything's obviously public
github一切显然都是公开的
there's a mailing list and lucky for you
有一个邮件列表，很幸运
all we have a weekly call on Fridays
我们每个星期五都有一个电话
I live in the Pacific time zone I make a
我住在太平洋时区，
call at 6:30 every morning or every
每天早上或每天6:30致电
Friday morning you all
星期五早上大家
luckily don't have to do that you can do
幸运的是不必做可以做的事情
yours at a more civilized 3:30 in the
您的文明程度是3:30
afternoon right so I encourage you if
下午吧，所以我鼓励你
this is something you are interested in
这是你感兴趣的东西
even if you're just an application
即使您只是一个应用程序
developer someone who's just you know it
开发一个只是你知道的人
wants to sort of keep an eye on things
想要关注事物
even if you don't know anything about
即使你一无所知
writing database drivers the most
最多编写数据库驱动程序
important takeaway of this particular
这个特殊的重要要点
effort for my career is I had always
我一生的努力
assumed database driver implementers
假定的数据库驱动程序实施者
were right next to compiler implementers
就在编译器实现者旁边
as the smartest people in all of
作为所有人中最聪明的人
computer science and I'm totally wrong
计算机科学，我完全错了
about that anybody can do this if you
关于任何人都可以做到这一点，如果你
can you know sort of read some
你能知道有点读吗
documentation and understand how bytes
文档并了解字节数
are ordered on the wire you can
可以通过电线订购
implement one of these drivers yourself
自己实施这些驱动程序之一
so I would absolutely love to have you
所以我绝对想拥有你
on the mailing list in getter in our
在我们getter的邮件列表中
weekly call even if you're just lurking
即使您只是潜伏，每周通话
but almost everybody has something to
但几乎每个人都有
contribute so we'd love to have you
做出贡献，所以我们很乐意拥有你
there ok and with that thank you all for
好的，谢谢大家
listening to me this afternoon and have
今天下午听我说
a good rest of the conference
会议的其余部分
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]